ILONA SKARGOVSKAYA

Front End Developer

in LinkedIn

Portfolio

☑ ilona.skars@gmail.com

+972 534-762-486

I am a skilled Full-Stack software engineer specializing in Front-End development. Focused to making great user experiences and delivering excellent software solutions. My skill set allowing me to craft immersive and interactive web experiences that seamlessly blend aesthetics with functionality.

WORK EXPERIENCE

React.js | React Native | Firebase | Node.js

Front End developer / Developers Institute (Israel)

nov 2023 - present

- Developing complex multilingual website for an international institution conducting business in 12+ countries, optimizing all cross browser and multi-platform compatibility using WordPress and JavaScript
- · Created multiple dynamic and browser compatible websites using React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript
- Developed a new user-friendly interface for the company's web app, leading to a 20% increase in user registrations
- Collaborating with UX designers and team of 5 to translate design concepts into fully functional user interfaces

Front End Developer / Say-Hi & i-CheckIn (Israel)

aug 2023 - jan 2024

- Developed 2 completely responsive, cross-browser websites, Dashboard and 2 mobile application using React.js, React Native, JavaScript, SASS, MUI and Tailwind
- Implemented state management solutions Redux Toolkit to manage complex application state
- · Created backend using Firebase and Cloud Functions for user profiles and data storage
- Integrated essential features such as filtering, JWT authentication, and interactive elements like maps and QR-code generation, enhancing the functionality and user engagement of web applications
- · Built backend for one of websites based on Node.js, PostgreSQL DB following the MVC pattern

Founder & Digital marketing specialist / Kids.by (Belarus)

2018 - 2022

- Produced full range of services from design to finished products, using plotter cutting, embossing and printing equipment. Developed comprehensive printing solutions for family events
- Created original video content and collaborated with brands and businesses to produce sponsored content, product reviews and promotions

Front End Developer / Minsk State Concert organization (Belarus)

2014 - 2021

• Built responsive websites for 40+ customers based on different CMS, using JavaScript and SASS

Website layout designer / Internet agency "WEBMEDIA" (Belarus)

2012 - 2014

- Developed fully responsive websites from scratch till production using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and CMS
- Utilized the best practices and coding standards to improve organic visitors to company websites by 70%

EDUCATION

Full-Stack developer

2023

• Developers Institute, TLV Coding Bootcamp (Israel)

Bachelor of Software Development

• Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics (Belarus)

2012 - 2016

Software Technician

• Minsk Radioengineering College (Belarus)

2008 - 2012

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React.js, React Native, Redux toolkit, Node.js, Firebase, Postgre SQL, SCSS (SASS), JWT, Bootstrap, MUI, GIT, Tailwind, Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Wordpress CMS, SEO, Influence marketing

LANGUAGES

English (fluent), Hebrew (intermediate), Russian (native)